# Reece Holmdahl, Software Engineer

Minneapolis, United States, +1 (651) 260-8968, reece@holmdahl.io

LINKS	LinkedIn, Website & Portfolio		
PROFILE	Inspired Software Engineer with 1.5 years of experience at OWC, where I led key development projects, including rearchitecting a critical data integration solution and migrating internal business solutions to Microsoft D365. Experienced with building business-facing products, supporting customer-facing products, Agile development, prototyping, front- and back-end frameworks, and high-level languages. Excellent communicator keen on including all perspectives and seeking improvement through constructive feedback. Excited to collaborate with diverse people across teams and contribute to interesting and innovative projects.		
EMPLOYMENT HISTORY			
Jun 2024 — Sep 2024	Seasonal Expeditor, Pursuit Collection	Seward, AK	
	Seasonal work immediately following undergraduate studies.		
Sep 2023 — May 2024	Shift Lead Barista, Caribou Coffee	Minneapolis, MN	
	Part-time barista and manager on duty during final year of undergraduate to focus on studies.		
Jun 2023 — Aug 2023	Seasonal Line Cook, Aramark	Bryce Canyon, UT	
	Seasonal work between semesters of undergraduate studies.		
Aug 2022 — Jun 2023	<ul> <li>Software Engineer I, Other World Computing</li> <li>Led the redesign of the Salesforce-ERP data integration solution, managing the entire process from scope definition to successful implementation, with guidance from the Staff Engineer.</li> <li>Crafted maintainable and reliable business-facing solutions, incorporating front-end frameworks, RESTful APIs, data caching and storage, and efficient data processing techniques.</li> <li>Skillfully communicated across departments, regularly engaging with stakeholders, department heads, and executives on high-priority projects and strategic initiatives.</li> <li>Refined code quality in my projects by using software design patterns, leveraging software packages, and following framework best practices.</li> <li>Drove the documentation efforts for our department's best practices and application bootstrapping within our department, promoting knowledge sharing and standardization.</li> </ul>		
Apr 2022 — Jul 2022	<ul> <li>Jr. Software Engineer, Other World Computing</li> <li>Gained expertise with the back-end tech stack and DevOps suite through practical training with the Staff Engineer and self-guided learning.</li> <li>Engaged in weekly cross-functional training with other engineers to explore different technologies and collaboratively solve problems.</li> <li>Effectively communicated the status of my sprint tasks and epics to my manager and stakeholders with clarity and transparency.</li> <li>Precisely executed end-to-end DevOps processes for an assigned set of solutions.</li> <li>Demonstrated outstanding performance as a Jr. Software Engineer, leading to a full-time position offer after just 4 months.</li> </ul>		
Sep 2021 — Jan 2022	Undergraduate Research Assistant, University of Minnesot Duluth	Duluth, MN	

- $\bullet \quad Applied \ my \ technical \ skills \ to \ support \ research \ at \ the \ University \ of \ Minnesota \ Duluth's \ Gamification \ and$ Transportation Lab.
- Developed an MVP back-end server for a mobile app using Node.js: implementing Auth0 for user authentication, leveraging Apache Cassandra for persistence, and serving basic API CRUD functionality with Express.
- Initiated the integration of Geotab's vehicle data API with the mobile app, successfully establishing the first programmatic connection to access the collected transportation data.
- Reported on progress during weekly status meetings to align project goals.

#### **EDUCATION**

Jan 2021 — May 2024

## Bachelor of Science, University of Minnesota

- College of Science and Engineering graduate with Computer Science major and Mathematics minor.
- Dean's List, Fall 2021

Aug 2019 - May 2021

## Associate of Arts and Sciences, Inver Hills Community College

Sep 2017 — Jun 2021

## High School Diploma, Eagan High School

SKILLS	Communication	Expert	C++	Experienced
	Collaboration	Expert	Python	Skillful
	Software Engineering	Experienced	Node.js	Experienced
	Backend Development	Experienced	ASP.NET	Experienced
	Agile Methodologies	Experienced	SQL	Skillful
	Git	Experienced	React	Skillful
	CI/CD	Experienced	Machine Learning	Beginner
	Automated Testing	Skillful	Prompt Engineering	Beginner
	RESTful APIs	Experienced		

#### EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Jul 2018 — May 2020

## FIRST Robotics Competition, Eagan High School

- Key contributor to FRC team 2220 for two seasons as the programming sub-team lead.
- Gained early insight into key Software Engineering principles like iteration, collaboration, design patterns, and documentation.
- Honed my problem-solving skills by solving time-critical problems in a real-world environment.
- Developed a razor eye for mistakes in code, since a software issue could destroy hours of work and cost thousands.

Sep 2021 — May 2022

## President of Alpha Sigma Phi, University of Minnesota Duluth

- Chosen by national alumni to be the president of a first-year chartered fraternity with 18 members.
- Worked closely with 6 members in leadership, solving problems related to funding, outreach, recruitment, and event holding.
- Skillfully navigated the demanding balance of work, school, and extra-curricular activities; later received the Arrowhead Award for outstanding service to a registered student organization.

#### REFERENCES

#### Steve Briggs from Other World Computing

fluffybriggs@gmail.com  $\cdot$  +1 (847) 345-2946

# Doug Abrahamson from Other World Computing

doug.abrahamson@outlook.com · +1 (815) 979-0329

#### Sheila Morales from Caribou Coffee

+1 (612) 600-9286